Hello everyone and welcome back
to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have a
wild lesson for you
at the elementary level.
That's right.
We are actually going to visit a farm.
So yeah, it's going to be fun.
We're going to see a lot of animals.
And not only that, but
we're going to learn a lot
of interesting words and
phrases in English today.
But before we get started, let's
take a look at vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
"We're not going to be
teaching you this song today.
Don't worry. You don't
have to listen to us sing.
" We do have a great word to start
us off. It's called "The Word is Country.
" A country. Okay, so
you know country as like
the United States,
Mexico, Mexico, China, etc.
But in this case, we are
going out to the country, not
out of the country, we're
going out to the country.
To the country, okay? The
country, or you might hear,
the countryside is a
place that's not like a city.
Right. So it's the opposite of
city. It means there's lots of grass,
it's very natural, there are very,
very few houses and people.
It's very quiet, so it's the opposite
of a busy city. It's the country.
And you'd have a lot of
animals. So usually, farms
are found on the countryside
or at the countryside.
In the countryside.
So usually, farms are
found in the countryside.
That's right, and I personally am a big
fan because it's so quiet and peaceful, so.
We can talk about that in a minute.
Let's listen to today's dialogue
first and then we'll be back to talk
about some of the words and phrases.
Isn't this great? I
always wanted to own a
farm, live out in the
country, grow my own food.
This is very beautiful.
Though I have to confess,
I don't know the first
thing about farming.
That's fine, don't worry about it.
What was that?
Relax. It was just a goat.
And that is just the cows that are
grazing over there. We can milk them later.
What was that?
Honey, seriously. It's just a sheep. Relax.
Relax. That was just the horses
and donkeys that are in the stable.
You know what? I don't think I can
hack it out here in the countryside.
I'm going back to the city.
All right, we're back. So obviously,
some people cannot go to the countryside.
That's right.
Some people get very, very upset.
In fact, there was a whole
TV show in America that
was about city people
living in the countryside.
See, they can do it, right? That's right.
All right. But before we
talk about that, why don't
we take a look at four key
words in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
The first word is the
name of an animal.
Okay, so you've all heard of
cows, but have you heard of goats?
A goat. A goat. All right.
So a goat is a strange looking animal.
It's kind of skinny.
And what do you get from a goat?
You can actually drink goats milk. Right.
And many people like to eat goats cheese,
which is cheese made from goats milk.
Mm-hmm. Okay. So a goat. Can you and
we heard that the sound that a goat makes.
So I think it's pretty
clear what a goat is.
And they're very common, as we say, in
farms, such as sheep and horses, cows, etc.
That's why, normally,
when they're in the wild,
they like to live in rocky
places, like mountains.
Right. That's why they say they're very
good climbers because they don't fall.
True. All right. And
well, if you have cows,
then they're probably
going to be grazing.
Okay. So to graze as a verb, it's something
we do. Well, we people don't do it.
Animals do it. It's a
way for us to describe
how animals like cows
eat means to eat grass.
Okay. So if your cows
or horses are grazing,
that means they're eating
grass somewhere out.
That's right. They're
walking. They stop.
They eat some grass.
They walk. They stop again.
It's a very slow
process. All right.
So cows are usually grazing
out in the countryside.
And well, once they finish
grazing and they get all
fat, then in the mornings,
you have to milk them.
Okay. So we drink milk. Milk is a thing,
but it's also a verb. So to milk something.
All right. And if you milk a cow is when
you extract the milk, the liquid from them.
Right. That's right. So underneath
a cow, there's an other or they're
underneath a cow. There
are others, which you have
to squeeze with your hands
to make the milk come out.
Okay. Interesting word as well. Other.
Right. It's like that big bag full of milk.
Exactly. So to milk
a cow. All right.
And you have cows out in
the field grazing and probably
your horses and donkeys
are going to be in the stable.
The stable is a place. Okay.
So this is something that's
often found on farms where the
horses or the cows
live. It's a it's a structure.
It's a building for
those animals. Okay.
So they're probably
separated in different little
rooms or compartments.
And that's called a stable.
So as you say, usually find horses and
cows and donkeys in there. That's right.
So stable is a way to protect
animals from the weather.
All right. Very good. So four
key words there as we just saw.
Why don't we listen
to this dialogue again?
And we'll be back soon.
Isn't this great? I always wanted to
own a farm, live out in the country,
grow my own food. This is very beautiful.
Though I have to confess,
I don't know the first thing about farming.
That's fine. Don't worry about it.
What was that? Relax.
It was just a goat.
And that is just the cows
that are grazing over there.
We can milk them later. What was that?
Honey, seriously. It's just a sheep. Relax.
Relax. That was just the horses
and donkeys that are in the stable.
You know what? I don't
think I can hack it out here
in the countryside. I'm
going back to the city.
All right. We're back. So now let's take
a look at fluency builder. Fluency builder.
You know, Marco, I have to confess.
I love fluency builder.
All right. And that's our first
phrase for today. I have to confess.
Okay. So to confess is to tell
someone something that's a secret.
Okay. So we can
confess with a priest. No.
So we can confess to a priest.
We can confess a secret to a friend.
Okay. But I have to confess
is a very common phrase.
It's a way for us
to start a sentence.
I have to confess. Right.
So you're saying, I have
to be honest with you. I
have to tell you the truth.
Exactly. So I have to
confess. I'm not a huge fan
of that sweater. Okay.
So I have to be honest.
I really don't like your
sweater. This is a way for
us to be more polite when we're
saying something that's right.
Right. And in this case, it was a girl who
was confessing and what she confessed
is her second key
phrase. I don't know the
first thing about farming.
Okay. So I don't know
anything about farming
is another way we could
say this or I don't know
a thing about farming.
But I don't know the
first thing about farming
means I don't even
understand what a farm is.
Okay. The first thing
is what is a farm.
I don't even understand
what a farm is for. This is a way
for us to say, I don't know
anything at all about this.
And if we change the noun, right, and
we can say for example, I don't know the
first thing about cars.
So I have no idea what
models they are or what
type of engine they have.
I don't know the
first thing about cars.
All I know is how to
turn them on. Right.
Or I don't know the
first thing about wines.
I'd love to learn about
wine, but I don't know the
first thing about it.
Okay. So it's a phrase that
you can use with many,
many different nouns, right?
I don't know the first
thing about architecture.
thing about English.
Right. Well, we do. And that's
why we're here to help you.
But this is a really
great phrase to
describe not understanding
anything at all about something.
Right. So this is
a really great way
to describe not knowing
anything at all about something.
Okay. And well, obviously, since she
didn't know the first thing about farming,
she ended up leaving. And
she said, you know what?
I don't think I can hack it
out here in the countryside.
Okay. So I can hack it.
He can't hack it. We use this
with the verb to be able to.
And it means I don't
think I can do this.
I think this is too hard.
Or maybe if somebody quit
right after a week at
the office and you can
say he couldn't hack
it. He couldn't hack the
pressure and he left. Exactly. So that means
to handle or to be able to handle or to
withstand. So I just don't
think I can hack the cold.
Right. I can't handle the cold.
It's too cold here. I'm moving
somewhere warm. All right.
So I'm sure you guys
will be able to hack our
dialogue one last time.
So let's listen to it and we'll be back.
Isn't this great? I
always wanted to own a
farm, live out in the
country, grow my own food.
This is very beautiful.
Though I have to confess,
I don't know the first
thing about farming.
That's fine. Don't worry about it.
What was that? Relax. It was just a goat.
And that is just the cows that are
grazing over there. We can milk them later.
What was that? Honey, seriously.
It's just a sheep. Relax.
Relax. That was just the horses
and donkeys that are in the stable.
You know what? I don't
think I can hack it out here
in the countryside. I'm
going back to the city.
All right. We're back.
So as you said, you're a
fan of the countryside
and about farming, right?
That's right. Well, I wish I
knew more about farming.
I don't know the first
thing about milking
a cow, but I do come
from a part of the world
in Illinois near Chicago,
where we have a lot of
farms and I appreciate
the quiet and it's nice.
I'll have animals around
and being able to go
on long walks without
cars and horns and bicycles.
And it is actually a
little bit refreshing to
be out in the countryside
sometimes and not even
have internet or cell
phone coverage or anything.
So it's just basically
you can't do anything
else, but relax, read
a book, talk to people.
Exactly. Now, an
interesting thing about this is
a lot of people take for
granted the countryside
because I've met many
people who live in the
city, who grew up in the
city and have never seen,
for example, a life
chicken. And when they see
it, they just freak out
and take pictures with the
chicken or a cow or
something, it's amazing.
That's really funny. Well, I
think it's very valuable skin.
I think there are
very valuable skills
that you learn being
out in the countryside like
how to cook for yourself.
There's no one else who
can cook for you or how
to get food from animals.
Or maybe you can't even
use a microwave, so how
do you cook without a
microwave or something?
That's right. And I think
the biggest problem
for city people when they
come to the countryside
is that it's dirtier. You know,
you get mud and there are bugs.
And I imagine some
of our co-workers
here having a very hard
time in the countryside.
Yes, indeed. So why don't you
guys come to our website EnglishPod.
com? Let us know what
you think about this.
Maybe you're very
familiar with the countryside
or have a relative
who's a farmer. It's great.
So visit us EnglishPod.com.
And if you have any
questions or comments, you
can leave them there as well.
Can't wait to hear
from you. Happy studies.
Bye bye.